Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today's lesson is an advanced level lesson.
我是Catherine，今天的课程是高级水平课程。
That means we'll be speaking using our normal English tone of voice and using some very,
这意味着我们会用正常的英语语速说话，并使用一些非常，
very difficult vocabulary and phrases.
非常难的词汇和短语。
So this is really good practice for all of you out there.
所以这对你们所有人来说都是很好的练习。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to change a little bit the dynamic of how it works.
我们会稍微改变一下节目的运作方式。
We're not going to look specifically at language takeaway or fluency builder.
我们不会专门讲解“语言要点”或“流利度提升”。
We're going to talk about the topic.
我们会讨论这个话题。
We are going to pick out a couple of different words and phrases that are used in the dialogue,
我们会挑出对话中使用的几个不同的单词和短语，
but we're mainly going to talk, just have a conversation and you can just listen and
但主要是聊天，进行一段对话，你们可以听，
study a little bit of what we're saying.
并学习我们说的内容。
So what is the topic today, Marco?
那么，Marco，今天的话题是什么？
Well today we're going to talk about the environment, specifically about our carbon footprint.
嗯，今天我们要讨论环境，具体来说是我们的碳足迹。
Okay, that is the title of today's lesson.
好的，这就是今天课程的标题。
I encourage all of you to listen to the context of that phrase and we'll be back in a moment
我鼓励大家听一下这个短语的上下文，我们稍后会回来
to talk about what it and some of these other phrases mean.
讨论它和其他一些短语的意思。
So what's your guys' take on all this global warming hysteria in the media?
你们对媒体上这些关于全球变暖的炒作怎么看？
It's pretty serious, man.
这很严重，老兄。
There have been tons of scientific studies and the scientific community says that the
有大量的科学研究，科学界表示
earth is heating up.
地球正在变暖。
We need to make some drastic changes to our lifestyle if we want to preserve our planet.
如果我们想保护我们的星球，就需要对我们的生活方式做出一些重大改变。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It sounds like a bunch of mumble jumble if you ask me.
在我看来，这听起来像是一堆胡言乱语。
The earth will save itself.
地球会自我拯救。
It survived the worst disasters in the past.
它过去经历过最严重的灾难都挺过来了。
I mean, honestly, we live in the boonies.
我是说，说实话，我们住在偏远地区。
There's no way anyone here is ever going to walk or bike to work, especially in the winter.
这里没人会走路或骑自行车上班，尤其是在冬天。
And we have no bus system.
而且我们也没有公交系统。
My house is 40 years old and it would take a lot of money to get it refitted to be green
我的房子有40年历史了，要把它改造成绿色环保
and energy efficient.
和节能的房子需要花很多钱。
Well, I don't really know if I believe in global warming either or whether or not it
嗯，我也不太确定我是否相信全球变暖，或者它
was our doing or a natural change the earth is going through.
是不是我们造成的，还是地球正在经历的自然变化。
But you have to admit that we're living pretty irresponsibly here in the West.
但你必须承认，我们在西方的生活方式相当不负责任。
I guess.
我想是吧。
I think the issue at hand is sustainability.
我认为关键问题是可持续性。
We've only got this one earth we can live on and our resources are quickly disappearing
我们只有这一个地球可以居住，而我们的资源正在迅速消失，
because of our own carelessness and our inability to think of anyone but ourselves and anything
因为我们自己的粗心大意，以及我们只考虑自己和
but the present.
眼前，不考虑其他人和未来的能力不足。
So like I was saying, we need to change the way we live.
所以就像我说的，我们需要改变生活方式。
We need to reduce our carbon footprint.
我们需要减少碳足迹。
But it doesn't have to be that drastic.
但不必那么极端。
Hybrid vehicles and solar panels are too expensive to be feasible right now.
混合动力汽车和太阳能电池板现在太贵了，不现实。
And we don't have to be hippies living off the land and buying everything organic either.
我们也不必成为靠土地为生、什么都买有机产品的嬉皮士。
Though it helps.
虽然那有帮助。
I carpool to work every day with some buddies of mine.
我每天和几个朋友拼车上班。
I have a rain barrel outside my house I use to water my plants and my lawn in the summer.
我家外面有一个雨水桶，夏天用来浇花和草坪。
And I make sure I always bring reusable bags with me when I get my groceries.
而且我确保去买菜时总是带着可重复使用的袋子。
And we just started using biodegradable plastic made from corn oil for takeout orders at my
我们家族餐厅的外卖订单也开始使用由玉米油制成的
family's restaurant.
可生物降解塑料。
Remember the three R's?
还记得三个R吗？
Reduce, reuse, recycle.
减少、再利用、回收。
Exactly.
没错。
It's just small, simple changes.
只是些微小、简单的改变。
Like buying energy-saving light bulbs.
比如买节能灯泡。
Starting a compost bin.
开始堆肥。
Recycling bottles and papers.
回收瓶子和纸张。
Using reusable water bottles.
使用可重复使用的水瓶。
Stop using disposable cups and cutlery.
停止使用一次性杯子和餐具。
Like the ones we're drinking out of?
就像我们正在喝水的这些？
Yeah.
是的。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So as you probably guessed, carbon footprint, it's pretty easy.
所以你可能猜到了，碳足迹，这很简单。
You're talking about a footprint is the evidence you leave if you're walking on sand, for example.
你在说足迹，比如你在沙滩上走路留下的痕迹。
Exactly.
没错。
And if we talk about carbon, we're talking about the element, right?
如果我们谈论碳，我们指的是这种元素，对吧？
Carbon.
碳。
Yep.
是的。
So carbon is something that is in everything, basically.
所以碳基本上存在于一切事物中。
It's organic.
它是有机物。
It can also, in the case of a carbon footprint, mean the amount of maybe waste or damage that
在碳足迹的情况下，它也可以指我们
we do to the earth or to the environment.
对地球或环境造成的废物或损害的量。
Right.
对。
So for example, you're driving your car.
所以举个例子，你开车。
We all know that the gas that is emitted from the exhaust pipe is CO2, right?
我们都知道从排气管排出的气体是二氧化碳，对吧？
And that contains carbon.
那里面含有碳。
So that's a way of seeing that you're leaving a footprint of carbon.
所以这可以看作是你留下了碳足迹。
You are damaging the atmosphere a little bit by driving your car.
你开车就在一点点地损害大气层。
So in talking about a carbon footprint, we talk about having a low carbon footprint,
所以在谈论碳足迹时，我们会说低碳足迹，
which is good, or a very high carbon footprint, which is bad.
这很好，或者碳足迹很高，那就不好了。
Right.
没错。
So there were a lot of interesting things coming up in the dialogue.
所以对话里出现了很多有趣的内容。
One of the first things was...
其中第一件事是……
Well, the first thing that they're talking about in this dialogue is they're having kind
嗯，他们在这段对话中讨论的第一件事，是有点
of an argument about whether or not global warming and global climate change really exists.
在争论全球变暖和全球气候变化是否真的存在。
Yeah, this is a very interesting part because some people say, well, global warming is happening,
是啊，这部分很有意思，因为有些人说，嗯，全球变暖正在发生，
global warming is real.
全球变暖是真实的。
And other people say, well, it's not real.
而另一些人说，嗯，这不是真的。
It's not really a problem.
这根本不是什么大问题。
This is just a phase that the earth will go through and like everything, it'll disappear.
这只是地球会经历的一个阶段，像所有事情一样，它会消失。
Well, I agree with people who say that the earth goes through phases because sometimes
嗯，我同意那些说地球会经历阶段的人，因为有时候
there are centuries that are hotter and sometimes there are centuries that are colder.
有几个世纪更热，有时候有几个世纪更冷。
But I think it's undeniable that there has been a large and immediate global climate
但我认为不可否认的是，在过去大概20年里，全球气候发生了
change in the last maybe 20 years.
巨大而迅速的变化。
Yeah, we're definitely speeding up maybe that cycle, right?
是啊，我们肯定在加速这个循环，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And I think that's great evidence of this and terrible evidence of this is the three
我认为这有很好的证据，而糟糕的证据是过去几个月里发生的三次
earthquakes, massive earthquakes that have happened in the last couple of months.
大地震。
I think that earthquakes like last year and like this year are really, really important
我认为像去年和今年这样的地震，是非常非常重要的
reminders that we do as humans influence the way that the world responds to us.
提醒，我们人类确实影响着世界对我们的反应方式。
I think I always see it as the earth kind of just shaking its back, kind of saying,
我总觉得这就像地球在抖抖背，好像在说，
get off me.
从我身上下来。
Stop it.
别这样。
That itches.
好痒。
Yeah, exactly.
是啊，没错。
That's the way I see earthquakes sometimes.
我有时就是这么看地震的。
But when they were talking about, well, is it real?
但当他们讨论，嗯，这是真的吗？
Is it not?
是不是真的？
They use a really interesting phrase and says, it sounds like a bunch of mumbo jumbo.
他们用了一个很有趣的短语，说：听起来像一堆胡说八道。
Mumbo jumbo.
胡说八道。
So this is a way to say that sounds like a bunch of garbage or it sounds like a bunch
所以这是一种说法，意思是听起来像一堆垃圾，或者听起来像一堆
of gibberish.
胡言乱语。
It sounds like a bunch of people are talking about something that doesn't really exist.
听起来像一群人在谈论一些根本不存在的东西。
So mumbo jumbo is basically something that's not really real or true.
所以“胡说八道”基本上是指不真实或不正确的东西。
I think don't you also, can you use it as somebody that's saying something you don't
我觉得，你是不是也可以用它来形容有人说一些你
really understand?
不太懂的东西？
Right.
对。
So if maybe I'm talking to you about something that's very academic and very scholarly, you
所以如果我跟你说一些很学术、很专业的东西，你
say, eh, sounds like a bunch of mumbo jumbo to me.
会说，呃，听起来像一堆胡说八道。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's what the person said.
所以那个人就是这么说的。
Ah, you know, the environmental problems are a bunch of mumbo jumbo.
啊，你知道，环境问题就是一堆胡说八道。
But it was really interesting because they were like, well, we have to save the earth
但很有意思的是，他们又说，嗯，我们必须拯救地球，
and well, and then there was actually a phrase here that was really kind of hard for me to
然后，实际上有一个短语对我来说挺难理解的，
understand when the person said, I mean, honestly, we live in the boonies.
当那个人说：说实话，我们住在偏远地区。
Boonies.
偏远地区。
So what does it mean by living in the boonies?
那么“住在偏远地区”是什么意思？
This is a very common word to hear in spoken English, especially with young people.
这是一个在英语口语中很常见的词，尤其是在年轻人中。
Boonies means we live far away from civilization.
“偏远地区”意思是住得离文明很远。
We live far away from cities.
我们住得离城市很远。
We live far away from everything.
我们住得离一切都很远。
So maybe these people live in the countryside or in a small village and they don't feel
所以这些人可能住在乡下或小村庄里，他们觉得
like they're affected by what people in the big cities do.
自己不受大城市里人们行为的影响。
Okay.
好的。
So if you say, oh, I live in the boonies, you're just saying, I live really far, really
所以如果你说，哦，我住在偏远地区，你就是在说，我住得很远，非常
far away.
非常远。
So this is a very common American word.
所以这是一个很常见的美国词。
I think you can also say boondocks, which is like that movie Boondock Saints.
我觉得你也可以说“boondocks”，就像电影《处刑人》那样。
But boondocks and boonies means very far away.
但“boondocks”和“boonies”都表示非常远。
So I could say, Marco, I'm not going to drive out to your house for a party.
所以我可以对马可说，我不会开车去你家参加派对的。
You live in the boonies.
你住在偏远地区。
Do you have any other ways that you can say that you live really far away?
你还有其他说法来表示你住得很远吗？
You live in Egypt.
你住在埃及。
You live in Egypt, which for us in America is obviously very, very far away.
你住在埃及，对我们美国人来说显然非常非常远。
Sometimes we say, oh, the youngs, exactly.
有时我们会说，哦，年轻人，没错。
People in New Zealand say that.
新西兰人这么说。
I've also heard people say, oh, you live where the wind turns around.
我还听人说过，哦，你住在风转弯的地方。
Really?
真的吗？
I like that one.
我喜欢这个说法。
It's like you live so far.
就像你住得那么远。
Oh God, you live where the wind turns around.
哦天哪，你住在风转弯的地方。
The end of the earth.
地球的尽头。
Exactly.
没错。
Wow.
哇。
So, well, there are a lot of different ways of saying that.
所以，嗯，有很多不同的说法。
So they were talking about different aspects of the environment, like that we heard the
所以他们讨论了环境的不同方面，比如我们听到了
word green or energy efficient.
“绿色”或“节能”这个词。
Okay.
好的。
So basically what they're doing is they're talking about some of the things they've heard
所以他们基本上是在讨论他们从媒体或电视上听到的一些关于人们应该做什么的事情。
in the media, maybe, or on TV about what people are supposed to be doing.
也许是从媒体或电视上听到的，关于人们应该做什么。
These are very abstract.
这些都很抽象。
That means these are very kind of big terms.
也就是说，这些都是很宽泛的术语。
Go green or be more energy efficient.
比如“走向绿色”或“提高能源效率”。
Yeah.
是的。
I've heard this, like, for example, when people say, oh, you have to be more green or go green.
我听过这个，比如当人们说，哦，你必须更环保或走向绿色。
That means more friendly towards the ecosystem, right?
那意味着对生态系统更友好，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So this is a very general suggestion and we can talk about specifics in a minute, but
所以这是一个非常笼统的建议，我们稍后可以讨论具体细节，但
this is a very general suggestion for thinking about the environment and doing things to
这是一个关于思考环境并采取行动帮助它的非常笼统的建议。
help it.
帮助它。
And so go green or be green is a way to be more environmentally friendly.
所以“走向绿色”或“环保”是一种更环保的方式。
We also have using energy efficient computers or light bulbs or TVs.
我们还有使用节能电脑、灯泡或电视。
The third thing that they talk about, and this is something that comes up a lot, is
他们讨论的第三件事，也是经常出现的一个词，是
sustainability.
可持续性。
Yeah, that's a big word that a lot of people like to use in this type of topic, sustainability.
是的，这是一个很多人喜欢在这种话题中使用的词，可持续性。
Right.
对。
So sustainability comes from the word to sustain.
所以可持续性来自“维持”这个词。
That means to hold out over time or to continue.
意思是持续下去或继续。
So you think about something, maybe sustainability is, I think, in many cases about doing or
所以你想一下，可持续性，我认为在很多情况下是关于做或
having habits, doing things that you can continue to do for a long time.
养成习惯，做那些你可以长期坚持的事情。
For example, driving a big SUV to work every day is not keeping in mind sustainability
例如，每天开大型SUV上班就没有考虑到可持续性，
because one day there will be no oil.
因为总有一天石油会用完。
So then what do we do?
那到时候我们怎么办？
Right.
对。
So that's not a sustainable action.
所以那不是可持续的行为。
Sustainable actions mean that we have less negative impact on the world.
可持续行为意味着我们对世界的负面影响更小。
Right.
对。
So basically what you're trying to do is to sustain, which means to hold, to withstand
所以基本上你要做的是维持，意思是坚持、承受
these habits, for example.
这些习惯，比如。
So when you talk about a sustainable ecosystem, it means that it has everything it needs and
所以当你谈论可持续生态系统时，意味着它拥有所需的一切，
it can continue to work for a very, very long time.
并且可以持续运行非常非常长的时间。
Right.
对。
So you can also talk about sustainable development, which we talk about in aid and giving aid
你也可以谈论可持续发展，我们在援助和向其他国家提供援助时谈到过。
to other countries.
向其他国家提供援助。
So sustainable development is trying to help other countries or other people in ways that
所以可持续发展是试图以其他国家和人民可以长期持续的方式帮助他们。
they can continue to do for a long time.
他们可以长期持续。
It's also very popular with tourism.
这在旅游业中也很流行。
They talk about sustainable tourism.
他们谈论可持续旅游。
Right.
对。
That means thinking about the environment and having tourism that can last forever,
意思是考虑环境，发展可以永远持续的旅游业，
not tourism that will destroy the environment because it's very harmful.
而不是因为非常有害而破坏环境的旅游业。
It's a very interesting topic.
这是一个非常有趣的话题。
And as you say, it's used in a wide range of cases, sustainable development, sustainable
正如你所说，它被广泛应用于各种情况，可持续发展、可持续
projects, sustainable tourism.
项目、可持续旅游。
There are a lot of different ways that people use this, but it's basically the same thing.
人们使用这个词的方式有很多种，但基本上都是一回事。
Right.
对。
It's in essence, it refers to that.
本质上，它指的就是那个。
Yes.
是的。
Keeping something going over time.
让某件事持续下去。
But I think the big question here is if you want to go green, if you want to be environmentally
但我认为这里的大问题是，如果你想走向绿色，如果你想环保，
friendly, what do you do?
你该怎么做？
Because it's not about big ideas.
因为这不是关于大想法。
It's about specifics.
而是关于具体行动。
It's about changing your everyday actions.
是关于改变你的日常行为。
Right.
对。
So these guys had a couple of ideas.
所以这些人有一些想法。
Yeah.
是的。
They came up with something like, for example, hybrid vehicles, which is a big thing now.
他们提出了一些东西，比如混合动力汽车，这是现在的大事。
Basically hybrid means two, right?
基本上混合意味着两个，对吧？
It's a combination of two or more.
是两个或更多东西的组合。
That's right.
没错。
So, you know the Sphinx in Egypt?
所以，你知道埃及的狮身人面像吗？
That's a hybrid.
那就是一个混合体。
Right.
对。
Between a man and a lion.
介于人和狮子之间。
Exactly.
正是。
Right.
对。
So a hybrid vehicle basically uses gasoline, but also electricity.
所以混合动力汽车基本上使用汽油，但也用电。
So they're actually very efficient because-
所以它们实际上非常高效，因为——
And they're quiet.
而且它们很安静。
They're quiet.
它们很安静。
And usually where you use up most of your gasoline is in traffic.
通常你消耗大部分汽油是在交通堵塞时。
Because your car is on, you're accelerating, you're braking, you're accelerating, you're
因为你的车开着，你加速、刹车、加速、
braking.
刹车。
So in this case, I think hybrid vehicles run on the electric engine until they hit, I think
所以在这种情况下，我认为混合动力汽车在达到每小时30英里之前是用电动引擎运行的。
it's 30 miles per hour.
我认为是每小时30英里。
And once you surpass that, then it switches to the gas engine, which obviously if you
一旦你超过那个速度，它就会切换到汽油引擎，显然如果你
have a constant high speed, it's more efficient, the combustion of the gasoline.
保持恒定高速，汽油的燃烧效率更高。
Exactly.
没错。
So a good example of a hybrid vehicle is the Toyota Prius.
所以混合动力车的一个好例子就是丰田普锐斯。
Right.
对。
I think it was like the first one commercially available.
我觉得它好像是第一款商业化的车型。
But now they have all kinds and they're actually trying to make entirely electric cars.
但现在他们有了各种类型，而且实际上正在尝试制造全电动汽车。
So lots of things to watch out for there.
所以这方面有很多值得关注的地方。
But they also talked about something for the house, right?
但他们也谈到了家里的一些东西，对吧？
So if you want to not just have a nice car that is environmentally friendly, but also
所以如果你不仅想要一辆环保的好车，还想
to do things with your house, what can you put on your roof?
在家里做些事情，那你可以往屋顶上放什么？
I think we've seen a lot of these.
我想我们见过很多这种东西。
These are called solar panels.
这些叫做太阳能板。
Solar has to do with the sun.
“Solar”和太阳有关。
So solar power, solar panel, that means energy that comes from the sun.
所以太阳能、太阳能板，意思就是来自太阳的能量。
So the sun.
就是太阳。
And a panel is like a pad or like some kind of device that can take the energy from the
而“panel”就像一块板子或某种设备，可以从
sun.
太阳那里获取能量。
Yeah.
是的。
It's really, really good.
这真的非常非常好。
Basically, in some places you have anywhere between eight to 12 hours of sunlight.
基本上，在某些地方，你每天有八到十二小时的日照。
So the whole day, these panels are absorbing energy.
所以一整天，这些板子都在吸收能量。
You can store them maybe in batteries and then just use them later.
你可以把它们储存在电池里，然后以后再用。
So basically you don't really need to use electricity that comes from coal or from nuclear
所以基本上，你不需要用来自煤或核
power plants because you want to turn on a light.
电站的电来开灯。
It doesn't really use up a lot of electricity.
它其实用不了多少电。
And there's no waste.
而且没有浪费。
It's all clean.
全是清洁的。
So my question for you, does Ecuador have a lot of solar panels everywhere?
所以我的问题是，厄瓜多尔到处都有很多太阳能板吗？
Because you guys have so much sunlight down there.
因为你们那边日照那么充足。
We don't really have a lot of them.
我们其实没有很多。
It's not a big commercial thing yet, but there are a lot of projects going around to help
这还不是一个大规模的商业项目，但有很多项目正在进行，以帮助
implement these things a lot better.
更好地推广这些东西。
For example, taking these technologies to the countryside where people don't have access
例如，把这些技术带到农村地区，那里的人们无法
to electricity by means of cables.
通过电线获得电力。
So they're implementing that there, getting them to use it.
所以他们正在那里推广，让人们使用它。
But it's still expensive.
但它仍然很贵。
That's the problem with solar panels is that, of course, it's an energy efficient way of
太阳能板的问题在于，当然，它是一种节能的
going.
方式。
It'll save you money in the long run, but up front, you've got to spend a lot of money.
长期来看能省钱，但前期你得花很多钱。
Well, here's a good way to use sustaining.
嗯，这里有个使用“自给自足”的好方法。
If someone in the countryside has solar panels in their house, it's a self-sustaining way
如果农村有人家里装了太阳能板，那就是一种自给自足的
to produce energy.
能源生产方式。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can spend on another place or a person.
所以你可以把钱花在别的地方或别人身上。
Exactly.
没错。
Actually, this is a very popular thing in many developed countries.
实际上，这在许多发达国家非常流行。
I remember when I was living in Chile, big buildings were being marketed as energy efficient
我记得我住在智利的时候，大型建筑在营销时都标榜自己节能
and green by showing that they can be self-sustaining.
环保，展示它们可以自给自足。
So basically, they would have solar panels on the roof.
所以基本上，它们会在屋顶上装太阳能板。
They would collect sunlight all day, and then they had big batteries that would store this
它们整天收集阳光，然后有大型电池储存这些
energy and then you can use it.
能量，之后就可以使用。
They were more efficient into keeping heat or keeping the cold.
它们在保温或保冷方面也更高效。
And also, what we saw in the vocab, they also had rain barrels.
而且，我们在词汇部分也看到，它们还有雨水桶。
So basically, collecting water from the rain, and then they can use this water, obviously,
所以基本上，收集雨水，然后显然可以通过
through a filtering system in order to be able to drink it or to wash your clothes and
过滤系统来使用这些水，以便饮用或洗衣服
stuff.
之类的。
But basically, they would say that it could reduce your carbon footprint by more than
但基本上，他们会说这可以减少你的碳足迹超过
50% and also the amount of money you would spend because you wouldn't spend so much money
50%，同时还能减少你的开支，因为你不用花那么多钱
on water, you wouldn't spend so much money on electricity or gas and things like this.
在水、电或煤气这些东西上。
That's awesome.
太棒了。
Well, one of the biggest concerns as far as environmentalism is water, where water will
嗯，环保方面最大的担忧之一就是水，50年后
come from in 50 years because there is a limited amount of fresh water in the world.
水从哪里来，因为世界上淡水资源有限。
And if we can reuse rainwater and collect it, I think it's brilliant.
如果我们能重复利用雨水并收集它，我觉得这很聪明。
So a barrel basically is like a big container, circular.
所以“barrel”基本上就是一个大容器，圆形的。
It's like a circle and it stands up on the ground or on a roof.
它像个圆圈，立在地上或屋顶上。
And it's brilliant because if you have a rain barrel that collects all this rain, and you
这很聪明，因为如果你有一个收集所有雨水的雨水桶，而且你
have solar panels, basically, you don't need gas or electricity to take a warm shower.
还有太阳能板，基本上你就不需要煤气或电来洗热水澡了。
You just have the solar panels that can heat up the rain barrel water and there you have
你只需要太阳能板加热雨水桶里的水，然后你就有了
a warm shower.
一个热水澡。
It sounds so nice.
听起来真不错。
You have sun-kissed warmth and you have fresh rainwater.
你有阳光般的温暖，还有新鲜的雨水。
But the whole water issue is a very popular topic.
但整个水的问题是一个非常热门的话题。
I recommend that any of our listeners read.
我建议我们的听众都去读一读。
There's a very interesting article that talks about don't worry about petroleum running
有一篇非常有趣的文章，讲的是别担心石油在50年内
out in 50 years.
会耗尽。
We're probably going to run out of our water before that.
我们可能在那之前就会把水用光。
And they project droughts and huge famine in places like India, like in the Middle East,
他们预测在印度、中东，甚至中国的一些地方会出现
even in places of China.
干旱和严重的饥荒。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Well, not to scare anyone.
嗯，不是要吓唬谁。
But yeah, it's interesting reading though.
不过，读起来确实挺有意思的。
Yeah, it's really good.
是啊，真的很不错。
Very serious stuff.
非常严肃的内容。
Well, the last thing that I think we should talk about before we listen to today's audio
嗯，在听今天的音频之前，我觉得我们最后应该聊聊
file again is the compost bin.
堆肥箱这个话题。
Now, this is maybe something that's hard to understand for someone who's never seen one
对于从没见过堆肥箱的人来说，这可能有点难理解。
before.
But basically, compost is, well, the verb is compost, to compost, but it's also a noun.
但基本上，堆肥这个词，动词是compost，意思是堆肥，但它也是名词。
But a lot of people, they don't want to throw away their food and their organic material,
但很多人不想扔掉他们的食物和有机材料，
things like flowers and food and biodegradable things.
比如花、食物和可生物降解的东西。
They actually reuse them.
他们实际上会重复利用它们。
They have a space in the backyard of the house where they throw away all the old food.
他们在房子后院有个地方，用来扔所有旧食物。
Nothing plastic, nothing non-biodegradable.
没有塑料，没有不可生物降解的东西。
And that over time turns into fertilizer or mulch for their gardens.
随着时间的推移，这些东西会变成花园的肥料或覆盖物。
So basically, you're putting it back into the earth.
所以基本上，你是在把它归还给大地。
Yeah.
是啊。
No, this is a very good option.
不，这是个非常好的选择。
And I remember seeing that even in Brazil, they have huge compost bins or compost places
我记得甚至在巴西，他们也有巨大的堆肥箱或堆肥场所，
that they fill up with this garbage.
用来装满这些垃圾。
And obviously, things that decompose start to emit methane gas.
显然，腐烂的东西会开始释放甲烷气体。
So they've found a way to harness this gas, transport it through tubes, and start using
所以他们找到了一种方法，来利用这种气体，通过管道运输，并开始使用
it.
它。
So actually having gas stoves with this methane gas.
所以实际上就是用这种甲烷气体来做饭。
That's brilliant.
太棒了。
So two uses, fertilizer and methane gas.
所以有两个用途：肥料和甲烷气体。
Yeah.
是的。
So there are a lot of options there to go green, to do your part to help the earth.
所以有很多选择可以走向绿色，尽自己的一份力来帮助地球。
Wow.
哇。
So let's listen again to the dialogue that we had today.
那么让我们再听一遍今天的对话。
Hopefully we've cleared up some of the things that were confusing for you, and we'll be
希望我们已经澄清了一些让你困惑的地方，我们马上
back in just a moment.
就回来。
So what's your guys' take on all this global warming hysteria in the media?
那么你们对媒体上这些关于全球变暖的歇斯底里有什么看法？
It's pretty serious, man.
这很严重，老兄。
There have been tons of scientific studies, and the scientific community says that the
有大量的科学研究，科学界说
earth is heating up.
地球正在变暖。
We need to make some drastic changes to our lifestyle if we want to preserve our planet.
如果我们想保护我们的星球，我们需要对我们的生活方式做出一些重大改变。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It sounds like a bunch of mumble jumble if you ask me.
要我说，这听起来像是一堆胡言乱语。
The earth will save itself.
地球会自我拯救的。
It's survived the worst disasters in the past.
它挺过了过去最严重的灾难。
I mean, honestly, we live in the boonies.
我是说，说实话，我们住在偏远地区。
There's no way anyone here is ever going to walk or bike to work, especially in the winter.
这里根本没人会走路或骑自行车上班，尤其是在冬天。
And we have no bus system.
而且我们也没有公交系统。
My house is 40 years old, and it would take a lot of money to get it refitted to be green
我的房子有40年历史了，要把它改造成环保节能的房子需要花很多钱。
and energy efficient.
而且还要节能。
Well, I don't really know if I believe in global warming either, or whether or not it
嗯，我也不太确定自己是否相信全球变暖，或者这到底是不是
was our doing or a natural change the earth is going through.
我们造成的，还是地球正在经历的自然变化。
But you have to admit that we're living pretty irresponsibly here in the West.
但你必须承认，我们在西方的生活方式相当不负责任。
I guess.
我想是吧。
I think the issue at hand is sustainability.
我认为当前的问题是可持续性。
We've only got this one earth we can live on, and our resources are quickly disappearing
我们只有这一个地球可以居住，而我们的资源正在迅速消失，
because of our own carelessness and our inability to think of anyone but ourselves and anything
因为我们自己的粗心大意，以及我们只考虑自己和眼前，
but the present.
不考虑其他人和未来的能力不足。
So like I was saying, we need to change the way we live.
所以就像我刚才说的，我们需要改变生活方式。
We need to reduce our carbon footprint.
我们需要减少碳足迹。
But it doesn't have to be that drastic.
但也不必那么极端。
Hybrid vehicles and solar panels are too expensive to be feasible right now.
混合动力汽车和太阳能板现在太贵了，不现实。
And we don't have to be hippies living off the land and buying everything organic either,
我们也不必成为靠土地为生、什么都买有机产品的嬉皮士，
though it helps.
虽然那样做也有帮助。
I carpool to work every day with some buddies of mine.
我每天和几个朋友拼车上班。
I have a rain barrel outside my house I use to water my plants and my lawn in the summer.
我家外面有个雨水桶，夏天用来浇花和草坪。
And I make sure I always bring reusable bags with me when I get my groceries.
而且我买杂货时总会带上可重复使用的袋子。
And we just started using biodegradable plastic made from corn oil for takeout orders at my
我们店里刚用玉米油做的可降解塑料来装外卖订单，
family's restaurant.
在我家的餐馆。
Remember the three R's?
还记得那三个R吗？
Reduce, reuse, recycle.
减少使用、重复利用、回收利用。
Exactly.
没错。
It's just small, simple changes.
就是些简单的小改变。
Like buying energy-saving light bulbs.
比如买节能灯泡。
Starting a compost bin.
开始堆肥。
Recycling bottles and papers.
回收瓶子和纸张。
Using reusable water bottles.
使用可重复使用的水瓶。
Stop using disposable cups and cutlery.
停止使用一次性杯子和餐具。
Like the ones we're drinking out of?
就像我们现在喝东西用的这种？
Yeah.
是啊。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So it's a very interesting topic, very debatable.
这是个很有趣的话题，也很有争议性。
We have Earth Day coming up, I think.
我想地球日快到了。
You have to turn off your lights for an hour.
你得关灯一小时。
That's right.
没错。
Earth Hour, Earth Day.
地球一小时，地球日。
So remember, reduce, reuse, recycle.
所以记住，减少使用、重复利用、回收再造。
The three R's.
这三个R。
Think about the way that you use things and try and reuse them if you can.
想想你使用物品的方式，尽量重复利用它们。
It's a very good topic.
这是个很好的话题。
We want to know what you think about it.
我们想知道你的看法。
And also if you have any suggestions or any comments about future advanced lessons, why
如果你对未来的高级课程有任何建议或意见，为什么
don't you tell us?
不告诉我们呢？
Come to EnglishPod.com and we'll see everyone there.
来EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里见大家。
Bye.
再见。
Britannica Life
大英百科生活